Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/vipul0sharma (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Hadoop

Java

Solr

Languages

English (Professional Working)
Hindi (Professional Working)

Certifications

Hybrid Cloud Conference – Pipeline Builder

Hybrid Cloud Conference – App Security and Threat Modeler

Vagrant Quick Start: Virtualized Development Environments

Essentials for Istio by Solo.io Introduction to Python

Honors-Awards

Hadoop Training

Vipul Sharma

Senior DevOps Engineer at nference Dehradun

Summary

"A DevOps Engineer with 1+ years of experience. I'm a Computer Science Undergraduate from University of Petroleum and Energy Studies, with a specialisation in Cloud Computing. Have a developer enthusiast mindset with knowledge about DevOps tools like Openstack, SaltStack, Zabbix etc. Love to code and solve problems"

Experience

nference

2 years 3 months

Senior DevOps Engineer

May 2021 - Present (10 months)

Bangalore Urban, Karnataka, India

DevOps Engineer

December 2019 - Present (2 years 3 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

Paytm

DevOps Engineer

July 2018 - December 2019 (1 year 6 months)

Noida Area, India

Working with Devops tools like SaltStack, Ansible for configuration Management. Whereas with Zabbix for the distributed system monitoring of the resources. Python Scripts for automation of various tasks. OpenStack for the cloud infrastructure management.

One Million by One Million (1M/1M)

Intern

April 2018 - September 2018 (6 months)

One Million by One Million (1Mby1M) is the first global virtual accelerator, headquartered in Silicon Valley. We aim to nurture a million entrepreneurs to

reach a million dollars each in annual revenue and beyond, thereby creating a trillion dollars in global GDP and ten million jobs.

Let's Get Hired (LGH) Initiatives Intern April 2018 - June 2018 (3 months)

LGH Initiatives is a not-for-profit initiative with a two-fold agenda:

Women Empowerment:

The first and the foremost intent is to ensure women empowerment by the way of offering an opportunity to the women to make a come-back and restart their careers as we support, guide and direct them to re-enter the formal employment. The intention is to help find opportunities for those women (be it housewives, divorces, widowed, a single mother, or any other special case) who have lost track of their careers and wish to re-enter the mainstream job market and seriously wish to re-ignite and re-start their careers.

Career Resynchronization

The second call for action is to help and support people in coming out of the clutches of unemployment, poverty, social evils and a bad-quality life. This is not only limited to people seeking rehabilitation but shall also act as a bridge for those undergoing depression to come back from the darkness and see again their life from the prism of positivity sans losing pragmatism. The intention is to create an ambience of opportunities in the network competent enough to absorb and offer a chance of a new lease of life to those looking to re-frame their careers and have the skill-set and willpower for the same.

la vafara Internship February 2018 - February 2018 (1 month)

La Vafara MT (registration code 80419919) is a registered non-profit association in Tallinn Estonia, Europe. Their major objective of NPA is to spread education and knowledge among students by a group of highly trained professionals with considerable work experience in the field of skill education.

UNV India
Online Volunteer
November 2017 - January 2018 (3 months)

Dehradun

Advocating for volunteerism and civic engagement in peace and development.

Unacademy

Unacademy Category Expert November 2017 - January 2018 (3 months)

Unacademy is an ed-tech company based in Bangalore, India, which offers free education to its users through videos. Unacademy is India's largest learning platform. it provides High quality lessons for passionate learners by expert educators.

Boston Analytics Summer Intern May 2017 - August 2017 (4 months) Gurgaon, Haryana, India

Boston Analytics (BA) is a strategy consulting firm which serves Fortune 1000 clients seeking powerful insights from data to drive their strategic decisions about growth.

Education

University of Petroleum and Energy Studies
Bachelor of Technology (BTech), Computer Science · (2014 - 2018)

St. Jude's School (2005 - 2014)